Welcome! In this video, we are going
to learn about focus filters on iOS.
You see what they are, how they work,
and how to use them in your app.
We'll go through a simple example,
look at the code, and show how
to update your interface
based on the user's current focus.
Focus is a system feature that helps
people stay focused by
reducing interruptions from
apps and contacts.
It is useful during moments like work,
rest, or personal time.
With Focus, users can choose which apps
and people are allowed
to send notifications.
Focus filters make this even better
by allowing apps to change
their behavior based on
the active focus.
For example, the Calendar app can show
only personal events
during personal focus.
The Mail app can show only
work emails during work focus.
Your app can also use focus filters
to show or hide content, switch accounts,
change appearance,
or reduce notifications, depending on
what the user is doing.
To understand how this works, let's look
at a simple diagram.
On the left side, we have the app.
This is where the developer defines what
can change using app intents.
For example, which content should be
visible based on the current focus.
In the center, we have the system.
The system reads what the app defines
and shows it in the focus settings.
On the right side, we have the user.
The user opens Focus settings and chooses
how the app should
behave when a focus is active.
This makes the experience more personal
and helps reduce distractions.
Now that we have seen the big picture,
let's look at a real example.
In this video, we'll create a focus
filter that lets the user choose to see
drinks, food, or both.
For example, during a work focus, the
user might choose to see only drinks.
This makes the menu simpler
and helps avoid distractions.
With this kind of filter, the app shows
only what the user wants in that moment,
making the experience
more focused and efficient.
To do this, we create a new focus filter
using the set focus
filter intent protocol.
This is where we tell the
system what the user can customize.
First, we define a
title and a description.
This will appear in the focus settings.
Then, we add two parameters,
showDrinks and showFoods.
These are boolean values.
They let the user choose what type of
menu items they want to see.
Both parameters have
default values set to true.
In the system settings, they
will appear as simple toggles.
We also define a display representation.
This adds a subtitle with the user
selections, like drinks or foods.
The suggested focus filters method
provides a recommendation,
for example, showing only
drinks during work focus.
Finally, in the perform method,
we take the user's choice
and update the app with that information.
Once we have the user's choice,
we apply them in the app.
We store these values in a property
called menu item filter
inside a shared model object.
This property is updated
every time the focus changes.
In the menu view, we use this property
to decide which sections should be visible.
The app can show only drinks,
only foods or both.
This keeps the interface updated in real
time and makes sure it
matches the current focus.
If you want to go further, focus filters
can also affect other parts of the app,
not just the interface.
For example, you can filter notifications
so only the most
important ones are shown.
You can also change the app's badge count,
To show only what matters.
These features make the
app feel even more focused.
But if you want to make changes when
the app is not open,
like your notifications, badges,
or widgets, you need
to create an app extension.
This lets your filter run in the
background and keeps
the experience consistent.
Thanks for watching!
I hope this video helps you understand
how to use focus filters in your app.
It is a great way to create a more
personal and distraction-free
experience for your users.
See you in the next video! Bye!