Hi! In this video you are going to dive
into the building blocks
that make system interactions
like shortcuts,
Siri and Spotlight possible.
If you already explored what a shortcut is
and how it fits into the Apple ecosystem,
you are ready to go one layer deeper.
App intents are how your app
communicates with the system,
making features discoverable,
actionable and smarter.
Whether you are aiming to integrate
with Siri, power up your widgets
or prepare your app for app intelligence,
understanding App Intents is essential
to unlocking seamless
contextual experiences.
This diagram illustrates the role of App
Intents as the bridge between
your app and the system features
users interact with every day.
At the bottom, we have your app
containing all your logic,
features and data.
On top of that sits
the App Intents layer,
which exposes specific actions from your
app in a structured, system-readable way.
Then, at the very top, you see powerful
system experience like Siri,
Spotlight and Shortcuts.
These green tiles represent
the users' facing features
that become smarter and more useful when
your app provides well-defined intents.
In short, App Intents are how
your app plugs into the wider Apple ecosystem,
enabling seamless, natural
and intelligent user experiences.
So now that we understand where
App Intents fits in, let's talk
about what an intent actually is.
An intent is a clear, self-contained
action that represents
something your app can do.
It's not a screen or a feature,
it's a specific task.
Like Log 500 mL of water,
start a strength workout or send 20 bucks to Alex.
Each intent is defined with the
information it needs to run,
like parameters, inputs and outputs,
so the system knows exactly
how to describe and execute it.
You can think of intents
as the vocabulary of your app.
The set of things it knows how to do,
described in a way that's both
human-friendly and machine-readable.
And here's where things
get even more interesting.
While, in the past, it was enough
to expose your app's main
features as intents,
Apple's new guidelines
encouraged a broader approach.
Everything your app does
should be an App intent.
This means every action,
no matter how small,
should be defined in a way that
the system can understand and interact with.
It's a shift toward
making your App more modular,
expressive and ready to work seamlessly
across the entire ecosystem.
Now that we have covered what App intents
are and why they matter,
it's time to look at the framework that
makes it all possible.
In the hands-on module, we'll focus on
the developer side
of the App intents framework,
exploring its capabilities,
understanding how to define and structure intents
and walking through lots of example code.
One of the best parts?
The entire framework is built to work
natively with Swift.
That means you can
define all your intents
and connect with system
features using just code,
not files or external
configuration needed.
These make it easier
to collaborate with teammates,
track changes through version control,
and keep your
workflow simple and scalable.
To wrap things up,
the goal of this model was
to help you better understand
the relevance of system
experience in the Apple ecosystem.
To get familiar with features like,
Siri
Shortcuts
and Spotlight
and to recognize that all of those are powered by
App Intents, defined by you, the developer.
These intents are what allow your app
to truly connect with the system
and deliver rich, personalized interactions.
There are countless possible use cases.
Your app should aim to support
all of those that make sense for your user.
Thanks for watching!
We hope it gives you a clear starting
point for making your apps more
intelligent, accessible
and deeply integrated.
Bye!