Hi there, my name is Sergio
and in this video we are going
to explore what a shortcut is.
How the Shortcuts apps fits into the user
experience and how
automations can create seamless,
contextualized interactions across devices.
Whether you're
looking to improve your own
workflows or make your apps more powerful
through integration,
understanding shortcuts is a key step in
building smarter experiences.
A shortcut is a custom sequence
of actions that can be
triggered manually or automatically
to perform tasks across
apps and system services.
Think of it as a lightweight automation
tool built right into the ecosystem.
For example, a user might create
a shortcut that logs their latest workouts
from the fitness app,
updates a spreadsheet
in numbers with this data,
and sends a summary to their personal
trainer via messages, all in one go.
Others might set up shortcuts that start a timer,
turn on "Do Not Disturb"
and open their Focus app when
beginning a deep work session.
From sending a daily
progress report via email,
to logging in using a health app,
to generating voices using
data from notes or calendar,
the possibilities are
broad and highly customizable.
For developers, supporting shortcuts
means empowering users
to integrate your app
into their everyday flows
without even opening it.
The Shortcuts app is Apple's Visual
interface for building,
managing and running shortcuts.
It provides a drag and drop style editor
where users can chain
together actions from both
system and third-party apps, to create
powerful automations.
No code required.
For developers, the Shortcuts app
is where your app's exposed
app intents come to life,
allowing users to discover and use your
functionality in entirely new contexts.
It is not just a power user tool.
It's a key part of how users extend
and personalize their Apple devices.
An automation is a type of shortcut that
runs automatically based
on predefined triggers,
like time of day, location,
device activity, or even interactions with
accessories such as NFC tags and AirTags.
Unlike regular shortcuts, automations
do not require manual input to start,
although some may ask for confirmation
depending on the context.
For example, a user might set up
an automation to start playing a podcast
when they connect to the car's Bluetooth
or to silence notifications when
they open a meditation app.
Developers can tap into this system
by exposing app intents that
users can incorporate into automations,
allowing your app to respond
to real-world triggers
and become part of a seamless,
context-aware experience.
At the core of every shortcut
or automation is an action.
a single task that
a user's device can perform.
As a developer, you are responsible
to define these actions
by exposing functionality from your app
through the App Intents framework.
The action you provide
becomes a building block
that users can include
in their own shortcuts,
making your app more accessible,
useful and integrated across the system.
By carefully designing meaningful,
context-aware actions,
you are not just adding a feature.
You are extending your app into
the user's daily routine
in powerful and personalized ways.
Thanks for watching,
and we appreciate your taking
this time to explore
the Apple shortcuts with us.
As you have seen,
shortcuts and automations
are powerful ways to create more fluid,
personalized the experiences
across Apple ecosystem.
And as a developer, you play a key role
in making that possible.
In our next video, we will dive deeper
into the App Intents framework.
We'll walk through how
to define and expose actions
from your app step by step.
See you there.