In the previous module, we saw how to
create an app intent.
Turn it into a shortcut, and make it
accessible through Siri and Spotlight.
That gave us several ways to expose
features from our app to the system.
But what you have built so far
is just the beginning.
Hello, my name is Sergio, and in this module,
we are going to
learn how to make App Intents parameterized,
adding a new layer of
interaction with the user.
Let's start by creating a second intent
called ProductDetailIntent.
It will present relevant information
about one of our products
without needing to open the app.
Here we declare a
dependency on our model class,
which we will use later
to look up product data.
Now let's look at the
CoffeeShop structure.
In the previous model, we saw how to
inject this dependency using
the AppDependencyManager.
Now let's update the ProductDetailIntent
to receive a parameter,
the product name that
the user can specify.
We use the parameter property wrapper
to define an optional string
that holds the product name.
Inside the perform method,
we check whether this value is already set.
If not, we ask the user
for it using request value,
which works in supported contexts
like Siri or the shortcuts app.
Now let's use this parameter to fetch
the actual product data from
the model and return its price.
Once your app is installed and compiled,
open the Shortcuts app.
Create a new shortcut.
Under the Coffee app,
select Open product details.
Then, add a second action, show result
and set it to display
the result of the previous intent.
Now test it.
Try entering a valid
product name like "Café".
You should see the correct price.
Try something invalid
like "Café com Leite".
and the result will be empty.
NIL
And that's it! We create a parameterized
app intent, process the input and return
a value based on it.
We also saw how to manually build
a shortcut to trigger that intent.
In the next video, we explore how to
provide other types of output
and how to create
shortcuts automatically.
See you there!