Hi! In this video, we'll show how to
customize the appearance of your app
shortcuts in the Shortcuts app.
This is not a common topic and it's not
well documented, but it
can make a big difference.
We'll explain step by step how to define
the colors that the
system will use when displaying
your shortcuts.
By default, when you create an app
shortcut, the system uses
your app icon with standard
colors.
But, you can change these colors
to better match your brand.
You can customize both the foreground
and the background of the shortcut tile.
To change the shortcut appearance,
you need to edit your app's info.plist.
You will add a section under
the CFBundleIcons key, where
you define color names.
These color names must match
colors in your asset catalog.
Here is the exact code you
should add to your info.plist.
The color names you define are up to you.
They don't need to be exactly ShortcutsForeground
or ShortcutsBackgroundTop.
What matters is that the names of your
info.plist match exactly
the color names in your asset
catalog.
Once that's done, create the matching
color sets in the asset catalog.
You can provide one or
two background colors.
If you use two, the system
will create a vertical gradient.
If you use just one, the
background will be solid.
The foreground color is used for the icon
and the text of the shortcut.
The background colors create the visual
base behind the icon.
This gives your shortcut a distinct
and branded appearance across the system.
Let's see a quick demo.
I added the keys to my
info.plist exactly as shown.
Then, in the asset catalog, I created
a white color called
ShortcutsForeground.
For the background, I used a gradient
from light green to a
bit darker, with the names
ShortcutsBackgroundTop and
ShortcutsBackgroundBottom.
After building and running the app,
I opened the shortcuts app.
Now, my shortcuts
appear with the new colors.
The gradient looks smooth
and the icon stands out nicely.
Customizing these colors gives your app
a more polished experience.
It shows attention to detail and improves
recognition inside the system.
Even though this is a small thing,
it helps your app stand out.
And that's it!
Now you know how to customize
the appearance of your app shortcuts.
It's a hidden feature, but it's easy
to implement and gives
a great visual result.
Thanks for watching!