Hello, everyone. Welcome. I'm Giovanna,
and today we'll be talking about
an essential concept for developing apps
in the Apple ecosystem,
which is system experience.
System experience is the deep
and consistent integration of an app
with native operating system functionalities,
enabling users to interact with the app
seamlessly throughout system-provided features,
even without opening it.
Hey Siri.
Play the System Experience class.
Some of the key technologies
provided by the system
to ensure this integration include
Spotlight, which allows content from
your app to appear in system searches enabling
users to discover and directly
access specific parts of your app
without manually opening it.
Siri, which lets your app respond
to voice commands,
offering customized actions
like send a message or log a task
through voice interactions.
Shortcuts, empowering your app to provide
reusable and automatable actions that
users can combine with other apps.
Ideal for creating quick and personalized
experiences without any UI.
Controls, available in the new Control Center,
allowing your app to expose
functionalities as system-accessible
buttons at any time.
Widgets, displaying information
or actions from your app directly
on the home screen, lock screen or StandBy,
enable users to interact
quickly without opening your app.
Live activities, providing real-time
updates on the lock screen and dynamic island,
perfect for tracking deliveries,
timers or live scores.
Focus integration, enables your app
to suggest content filters or adapt
its behavior based on the user's current context,
such as work,
personal or sleep modes.
And hardware interactions,
like the action button or Apple pencil gestures,
allowing your app to respond to physical,
customizable actions like triggering
features or activating shortcuts quickly.
It's essential for your app to be deeply
integrated with the system to meet user
expectations and remain relevant.
With Apple Intelligence,
users will increasingly access your app's
functionality without even opening it,
making these integrations
more important than ever.
Fortunately, all the technologies
mentioned earlier are
already available, and you can
start preparing your app right now
for this growing demand.
The good news is that implementing these
integrations require far less code
and effort than it might
initially seem.
This seamless, proactive experience
is quickly becoming the
standard user expect,
shaping the future of interaction
across the Apple ecosystem.
Thank you so much
for your time and attention.
Throughout this course, our goal
will be to deepen your knowledge about these
native technologies,
exploring in detail how they work and the
possibilities they offer.
You'll see multiple hands-on examples
to help you clearly understand
and implement these integrations.
Ultimately, we aim to empower you
to confidently identify use cases
and integrate them effectively
into the apps you are developing.
Until the next video!