Hello! In the previous videos,
we explored how to use App
entities and entity queries
to improve the interactions between
our app and the system through Intents.
Now let's see how we can adjust our
widget to take advantage of this setup,
and also introduce a new
type of widget, Control Widget.
Let's start with a quick
update to our coffee widget.
Here's the coffee widget entry view.
Since our Intent is already encapsulated
into the configuration,
we just need to read the product,
optional name from it.
This is the key property that allows us
to retrieve the correct menu item.
Now let's create
something new, a Control Widget.
Control widgets allow your app
to interact more deeply with the system,
include the control center, lock screen
and even the action button
we will cover in the next module.
Like interactive widgets, Control Widgets
can also use Intents to perform actions.
For this example,
we'll reuse our Open Favorites Intent
to create a simple Control Widget
that opens the Favorites screen in the app.
Here's how we create it.
Let's break it down.
It conforms to the
ControlWidget protocol.
The body property returns
a ControlWidgetConfiguration.
We use a StaticControlConfiguration,
which defines a unique kind,
a string identifier for this widget.
Inside the closure,
we define the actual widget UI.
In this case, a ControlWidgetButton
that triggers our OpenFavoritesIntent.
We also define a displayName
and a description,
which helps users
understand what this widget does.
Next, we need to publish
it in our widget bundle.
We simply add the new widget to the
bundle by including FavoritesControlWidget
in the body.
Now we are ready to test it.
Add a new Control and look
for the coffee favorites widget.
Add it to the Control
Center and resize it as you like.
You'll see that it works
across all widget sizes,
and when you tap it, it opens your app
directly in the Favorites screen.
In this module, you have seen how to use
App Entities and Entity Queries
to expose concepts from our app to the
system through intents.
Apply this in both
interactive and control widgets.
These tools give our app better
integration with iOS and a smoother
experience to users.
In the next module, we explore even more
types of interactions
powered by App Intents.
Bye.