Hello! In the previous video,
we created an App Intent that look up
a product in our Coffee Shop.
We explore how to pass
parameters into intents,
how to return the
product price as a value,
and how to show a dialogue as output.
We also use the intent to manually create
shortcuts in the Shortcuts app.
In this video, let's go one step further.
We'll explore how this intent can
integrate more deeply with Siri.
and how it can return a custom SwiftUI
view as part of the response.
This let us show more refined
and detailed content,
making our interactions even richer.
Let's begin by creating a shortcut
for our Open Product Details intent.
We will rename it to my Coffee shortcut.
Now, if you ask Siri,
"Hey Siri, my coffee shortcut?"
It will ask us: "which product do you want?"
We can reply with something like
"espresso" or "panini" and see you return
the price of that item.
Just like that, we are interacting
with our app intent through natural voice.
But we can take this even further.
Let's create the shortcut programmatically,
so it's available by
default when the user installs the app.
In our project, we will add a new
shortcut to the CoffeeShortcutsProvider.
This class conforms to the
AppShortcutsProvider
protocol and defines available
shortcuts through the
AppShortcuts property.
Let's include both the shortcut created
by Giovanna in the previous model and
a new one for product details.
Once the app is installed,
we can open the shortcuts app.
Go to the coffee section and see both
the open favorites and show product detail
shortcuts already available.
Let's try them out.
We can define up to 10 shortcuts this way,
and all the custom phrases we have
specified will work with Siri.
Now let's enhance our intense output
by including a custom SwiftUI view.
To do this, we'll make our IntentsPerform
method conforms to "ShowsSnippetView",
in addition to the other protocols.
We'll return a view called
"ManualItemIntentCard",
which is a pre-built SwiftUI view that
shows the selected product detail.
Here is the updated intent.
Let's see this action.
Ask Siri: "Hey Siri,
show product in coffee app".
It will prompt you to pick a product.
On receiving your answer, Siri will speak the price
and show a detailed SwiftUI View
with the product's image, name and more.
This is a big step
forward in user interaction.
Now we are combining voice,
visual interface and app logic naturally.
There's still room to improve.
For instance, in the next module,
we explore how to include parameters
directly in the activation phrase.
So users can skip the
prompt and say something like,
"Show espresso in
Coffee app..." right away.
In this video, we have
created a shortcut programmatically.
We see how to
interact with it using Siri.
We return a custom SwiftUI
view as output for our intent.
And in the next video, you'll see how to
configure a widget that uses these intent
parameters as its inputs.
See you there!