Hello, in this video I will present
usability guidelines for designing system
experience with AI agents
to create more intuitive and transparent
interactions that align
with user expectations.
But first, let's understand what an AI
agent is by definition.
An AI agent is an intelligent system
that perceives the environment,
makes decisions and executes tasks without the
need for constant human interaction with
the interface, such as Siri.
It's important to remember that these
guidelines were partially based on
Nielsen's 10 usability heuristics,
which have been proven over the years.
And since this is an interaction between
humans and machines,
they can be applied to AI agents.
Let's present these guidelines.
First, set clear expectations up front.
Users must know what the AI agent
is capable of and what it is not capable of,
meaning they should be informed about
these limitations and capabilities
in a simple and objective way,
avoiding the creation of unrealistic expectations.
For example, an app intent of health tips
in a health habits app.
The intent could be: "Get wellness tips
and Health Habits" and receive a response like,
"What topic would you like a tip on?
Remember, I can't
provide medical diagnoses."
This way, the app intent would be
configured that the user clearly
understand the assistant's,
capabilities and limitations,
avoiding unrealistic expectations.
Second, match the agent's behavior with
the user's context and norms.
The AI agent must identify the context
and the moment the user is in,
so that they are not interrupted or the language
adapts to the cultural context.
For example, an app intent configured
to prevent the user from receiving reminders
or notifications while in a meeting.
This way, it could detect that the user
is in a meeting through the calendar
and once it has ended,
send a reminder or notification.
The app intent would respect
the user's context,
avoiding notifications at undesired moments.
Third, provide
transparency and explainability.
Based on the first usability heuristic,
visibility of system status.
The AI agent must provide clear feedback
on decision, which can be done through
a simple justification or an interface
that shows how it arrived
at that recommendation.
For example, an app intent of work directions
in a map's application.
The intent could be: "Get directions
to work" and would return with route options
based on time and distance
and the best option.
In this case, the app intent would
provide clear justification to the user
about why that route was suggested,
allowing them
to understand the system's logic.
Fourth, support user
control and easy escapes.
Based on third usability heuristic,
user control and freedom.
The user must have control over the AI
being able to reveal, correct,
confirm and even cancel what
is presented easily.
The final decision must
always belong to the user.
For example, an app intent of enhanced
image in a photo editing app.
The intent could be: "Get auto enhance"
Once done, it could show the result of
the photo with options to change contrast,
brightness and saturation.
This app intent would ensure that
the user has total control,
preventing undesired actions
and allowing quick adjustments.
Fifth, handle errors
and uncertainty gracefully.
Based on ninth usability heuristic,
help users recognize, diagnose
and recover from errors.
The AI agent must recognize when it's
wrong or uncertain and
handle this intuitively.
This includes avoiding risky actions,
providing clear error messages and always
offering the user a next step.
For example, an app intent of add to
playlist in a streaming music app.
When a song was playing, the user could
activate the intent.
Add music to playlist Workout and receive
a response like, "I couldn't find the
Playlist Workout.
What would you like to do?"
and would give the options.
Create a new Playlist called Workout
or choose an existing playlist.
This way, the app intent could be
configured to handle cases where
the requested playlist is not found,
responding in a friendly way and offering
alternative actions.
Sixth, enable
feedback loops and learning.
A simple way to collect feedback is
to offer ratings or quick
surveys after an interaction.
This allows the system to be continuously
adjusted based on users' response.
For example, an app intent of movie
and series recommender in a streaming app.
The intent could be
recommend a TV series.
The app would respond with a suggestion
and follow feedback options,
"Love" or "Suggest less".
Depending on the user's choice,
the app would adjust its future suggestions,
making them more personalized and aligned
with their tastes over time.
Seventh, learning from
user behavior over time.
Allow the AI agent to learn from user
preference over time
in a transparent manner.
Personalization proves the experience,
but must be done with the
user's consent and control.
For example, an app intent of a schedule
meeting in a meeting app.
The intent could be "Schedule a meeting for tomorrow"
and receive a response like,
"It looks like you usually schedule
meetings at 9am, so I will use that time.
What do you want to call it?"
If the user confirms the meeting is created,
the app intent would learn
the user's preferred times with their
permission to enhance future experience.
These are some guidelines for creating
more efficient and effective app intents.
By following these practices,
you improve your app's integration with the system
and deliver a smoother user experience.
I hope you enjoyed our content about
design for app intent.
Thank you for your time and attention.
See you later. Bye!