Hi! In this video, we are going to talk
about a feature that
connects hardware and software
in a very practical way, the Action Button.
Many people don't
know about it, but it can be
a powerful way for users to interact
with your app, especially when
combined with shortcuts and app intents.
By the end of this video,
you'll know what the Action
Button is, how it works, and how
to use it with the shortcuts you created
during this course.
The Action Button is a physical button
found on some Apple devices, like certain
iPhone models and the Apple
Watch Ultra. On devices that
support it, the button replaces or adds
two traditional controls
and lets the user customize
what it does. For example, it can open
an app, run a shortcut,
or start a system action.
It's a quick way to do something even
when the screen is locked.
Because it's designed to be
used fast and often without looking at
the screen, the best
actions are the simple ones.
Many people use it to open the camera,
turn on the flashlight,
start a voice recording,
or activate a focus mode. These are all
the things that work well
when they happen right away,
without extra steps. For us developers,
the best part is that we
don't need to change anything.
If we already created a shortcut using
app intents, the user
can choose that shortcut
for the Action Button. This is done in
the device settings.
So, just by supporting app
intents, your app is already ready to
work with the Action Button.
It's another way to make your
app more useful. Let me show you how this
works. I'll open the
Settings app on my iPhone, go to
the Action Button section, and pick one
of the shortcuts we
built earlier in the course.
The system allows me to assign it to the
button. Now, every
time I press the button,
that shortcut will run. No extra steps
needed. This is a great
example of how app intents make
our work more flexible and powerful.
Make sure the Action Button
gives a good experience,
there are some guidelines we should follow.
The action should be quick and
simple. It should not
ask the user for extra input or confirmation.
The user might press the
button while the device
is locked or in a pocket. So, the action
should run right away.
It's also a good idea to give
some feedback, like a sound, a vibration,
or something on screen.
This helps the user know
that the button worked. And finally, use
short and clear labels for your actions.
Three words or less is a good rule.
And that's it for this video.
The Action Button may seem like a
small detail, but it gives users
another easy and direct way to use what
we have built. And if you
are already using app intents,
you're almost done. Thanks for watching,
and see you in the next lesson. Bye!