Hello everyone, welcome! In today's video
we are going to dive
deeper into one of the most
iconic features of the Apple ecosystem,
Siri. Our main objective
is to understand what Siri
really is, how it works, and what it
enables users to do across Apple devices.
Whether it's through voice commands,
smart suggestions,
or deep app integration,
Siri plays a key role in making
interactions more natural and intuitive.
And with the arrival of Apple Intelligence,
it's about to
become even more powerful.
Siri was introduced in 2011 as the
world's first widely
available virtual assistant,
with the goal of helping users interact
with their devices
using natural language.
Over the years, it has evolved from
handling simple voice commands,
like setting alarms or sending messages,
to supporting a wide
range of functionalities,
including controlling smart home devices,
launching apps,
providing proactive suggestions,
and executing custom shortcuts.
Its core purpose has always been to make
everyday tasks faster, more convenient,
and more accessible by reducing
the friction between
the user and the technology.
Today, Siri can be used in a wide range
of practical scenarios
across Apple devices.
For example, on an iPhone, a user can say
"Hey Siri, send a message to João saying
"I'll be there in 10 minutes."
And Siri will compose the message,
confirm the content,
and send it via the Messages app.
Another common use case is asking
"Hey Siri, what's the weather like tomorrow in São Paulo?"
Which brings up
the weather app with a spoken
summary and visual forecast.
On Apple Watch, users can lift their wrist and say
"Start an outdoor walk."
And Siri will begin tracking the workout instantly.
For productivity, users can say
"Remind me to call
Anna when I get home." And Siri will use
geolocation to trigger that
reminder at the right moment.
Siri can also run custom shortcuts.
For instance, a user might say
"Hey Siri, order my usual coffee."
Which triggers a preconfigured shortcut
in a full delivery app.
These examples show how Siri
enables fast, contextual,
and hands-free interactions
that go beyond basic voice commands,
and enhances in the user experience through
intelligence automation.
Despite all its capabilities,
Siri still has some important limitations.
It may occasionally
misinterpret what the user says,
especially in noisy
environments or when dealing with less
common names and commands.
In more complex requests, it can struggle
to maintain the context of a conversation,
requiring the user
to repeat or rephrase instructions.
Additionally, while Siri
supports multiple languages,
its performance can vary.
Some languages or regions have more
limited functionality compared to English.
These limitations can affect
the overall user experience,
particularly for users relying on Siri
in non-English contexts
or expecting more natural,
conversational interactions.
With the introduction of App Intelligence,
many of Siri's current
limitations are expected to be
significantly reduced.
App Intelligence brings a new level
of understanding to Siri by combining
on-device processing with
large language models,
allowing for more accurate interpretations
of user commands, even when they
are complex or conversational.
This means Siri will be better
at following multi-step instructions,
remembering context
between interactions, and understanding
more natural language
without requiring perfect phrasing.
Another major improvement is
the use of personal contexts.
Siri will be able to draw from
the user's calendar, messages, emails,
and files, securely and privately
to provide smarter
and relevant responses. For example,
you might ask, "When is my
next meeting with Lucas?"
or "Send the file Anna shared with me last week."
And Siri will know exactly
what you are referring to.
In addition, Siri will be integrated
with ChatGPT, allowing users
to seamlessly access even
more powerful AI capabilities
when needed, such as writing an email,
draft or brainstorming ideas,
always with user permission. Altogether,
App Intelligence transforms Siri from
a command-based assistant in a truly
intelligent personal companion
that understands the user's world.
Thank you so much for your time
and attention. In this video,
we explore what Siri is,
how it works today, and how it's
about to evolve with the power
of App Intelligence.
As we continue through this course,
our goal is to help you
understand how to make your app
accessible through Siri using the right
technologies like App
Intents and shortcuts.
You'll see practical examples that show
how to implement these
integrations step by step.
It's important to remember that users are
increasingly expecting to interact with
apps using voice and natural language.
And with the improvements coming to Siri,
these expectations will only grow.
Making your app available through Siri is not
just a nice-to-have,
it's become essential. See you, bye!