Hi! In the last video, we learned how
to create an app entity to represent
a concept exposed by our app to the system.
We also explored how to use queries
to look up these entities and how
to integrate these into the app intents.
In this video, we are going to take this
a step further and use these intents
to create shortcuts, both
manually and programmatically.
Let's start by opening the Shortcuts app.
Tap the Add button to create a new shortcut.
Let's call it "Coffee".
Now, choose the action
"Open product details".
When you tap on "Product", we see a list
of items. These come
from our suggested entities.
As we start typing, the system call our
matching string function
to return the matching results.
Let's pick up a product. And done!
We now have a shortcut that uses our app
entity as a parameter.
We can also define this shortcut in code.
Let's take a look at
"CoffeeShortcuts.swift".
Notice the use of
"product" in the phrases.
This is only possible because we are
using an app entity, allowing us
to create dynamic, context aware phrases
that make Siri interactions
more natural and conversational.
Back in the Shortcuts app,
let's try it out.
Create a new shortcut again, search for
the "Coffee" actions,
and choose "Open product details".
Now tap on "Choose a product", and once
again, we see the menu
items from the query.
Type in a name "Triggers
our matching string function".
Let's test this with Siri.
Show espresso in coffee.
Siri understands the product name
and passes it straight to our intent.
This kind of interaction, where the user
speaks naturally and the app responds
meaningfully, is only
possible because of app entity.
So, in this video, we saw how
interactions with app intents through
shortcuts and Siri become much more fluid
and powerful when using app entities.
In the next video, we explore how to
bring this same power
to widgets. See you soon!