Hi, so far you have
gone through several steps.
We create an app intent that retrieves
information about a product in Coffee Shop
shop using a parameter.
We made this intent return a value,
a dialog and a view
to present the search result.
This allowed us to interact with
the intent through shortcuts and Siri.
We create shortcuts both in the
Shortcuts App and programmatically.
Now, it's time to use the intent
parameters to populate a widget.
Let's dive in.
Let's start by creating an additional
target of type widget extension.
We'll call it Coffee Widget.
This creates
a template structure containing
the widget itself in the
CoffeeWidget.swift file.
the CoffeeWidgetBundle, which can expose
multiple widgets from the same extension.
We'll use just one for this example.
We also update the target membership
for any coffee app files
we need in the widget.
Include product detail
intent and its dependencies.
Here we are using App Intent
configuration to configure
the widget using our intent.
We have, kind, a unique identifier,
in this case, CoffeeWidget.
Intent, the app intent used as
configuration input,
product detail intent.
provider, a timeline provider that
determines how and
when the widgets updates.
and content, the view that renders widget
content using the provided entry.
The widget content is played using
CoffeeWidgetEntryView,
which we will define soon.
To use an intent for
widget configuration,
our intent must conform to the widget
configuration intent protocol.
The next step is therefore creating the
provider for those entries.
The provider is a type of
App Intent Timeline Provider.
It supplies data for three cases.
Placeholder, a temporary UI shown before
real data is loaded.
snapshot, a quick preview
based on the current state.
Timeline, a series of widgets
updates is scheduled in time.
This structure depends
on the entry structure.
This is the model passed to the widget
view that holds the timestamp and the
intent as a configuration element.
Now let's implement the view that
displays the product data in the widget.
This view uses the configuration from the
intent to extract the product name
and look it up in the model, showing the
corresponding widget card.
Finally, let's expose our
widget using the widget bundle.
The main attribute marks this as an entry
point of our widget extension.
We register our model dependency using
AppDependencyManager.
Now we can.
Tap and hold the Home screen.
Add it.
Add widget.
Search for coffee and select the widget.
Tap Edit widget and
provide a valid product name.
The widget now updates with info about
the selected product.
In this video, we explore how to
configure and use a widget
powered by an app intent.
In the next module, we'll dive deeper
into interactive App Intent use cases.
See you there, bye!