Hello, I'm Luna. In this video,
we will discuss the evolution of user interface
and how artificial intelligence
is introducing a new paradigm that will
completely change the way we interact
with computers and devices.
To understand this shift,
let's explore the two major paradigms that
have shaped this evolution.
First paradigm: Batch Processing.
Emerging around 1945,
this model required users to define
the entire workflow that the computer
needed to execute, run the program,
and then wait for the result.
An example of this would be processing
bank transactions for payroll.
A batch of punched cards was inserted
into the machine, which calculated
the employee's salaries in sequence.
Without human intervention during the process,
the interaction with the
computer was extremely limited.
If the outcome was incorrect or contained errors,
it could take days to apply
corrections and then
wait for new results.
Due to the limitations of this model,
a second paradigm emerged.
Command-Based Interaction
Introduced around 1965,
this model allowed users to issue commands
and receive responses from the computer,
enabling continuous
adjustments based on the results.
This model evolved through three
generations of interface technology.
First Generation, Command Line Interface
Second Generation,
Full-Screen Text-Based Terminals.
Third Generation,
graphical user interface
The last one has remained dominant for
almost 40 years, ever since
the launch of Macintosh in 1984.
The key advantage of graphical user interfaces
is their visual feedback after each command,
providing users with
a clear status update.
This format has dominated for over 60 years,
but now AI is changing
the dynamics of interaction,
giving rise to the third paradigm.
Intent-Based Outcome Specification
In this model, the user describes
what they want, and the system powered by
artificial intelligence interprets
the user's intent and executes the necessary
actions to deliver
the expected results.
For example,
requesting to generate an image
Unlike command-based interaction,
where hundreds of commands might be needed
to achieve the desired outcome,
in this paradigm a single prompt
can generate the intended image.
Although this approach is revolutionary,
it is important to note that the AI agent
may misinterpret the user's intent.
The user may fail to articulate their
requests correctly,
leading to unexpected results.
To minimize errors and enhance
the user and system experience
There are guidelines that when applied
to AI agents, make intents more effective
and efficient, and will be
presented in the next video.
I hope you enjoyed the discussion.
Thank you for your attention,
and see you next time. Bye!