Hi! In this video, we are going to create
our very first App Intent.
This will be our first step as we begin
working with App Intents in our project.
We'll take a look at the
basic structure of an intent,
what kinds of results it can return,
and how to use it to open
a specific screen in our app.
At the end, we will test our first intent
and see it working in practice.
Now let's take a look at the code.
This is where we
create all our App Intents.
What you see here is the
basic template of an intent.
At the top, we need to import
the AppIntents framework.
Then, every intent must
have at least three things.
A title, a description
and a perform() method, which is where
we define what the intent should do.
Our first intent will be used to open
the favorites tab in the app.
When it runs, it will launch the app
and switch to the favorite screen.
To make that happen, we need to
set the property
"OpenAppWhenRun" to true.
So, the system knows it should open
the app when the intent is triggered.
Inside the perform() method,
we add the navigation logic
to select the favorites tab.
Since we don't need to return any data
here, we just call .result at the end.
To make the navigation work,
we are using @Dependency.
which is a way to access the app's shared
model directly inside our intent.
It lets us control part of the app,
like which tab is selected,
without testing anything manually.
Here, at the coffee app Swift file,
you can see where the module is registered,
so the intent knows how
to access it when needed.
Now let's test our intent in the
shortcuts app. I'll create a new shortcut
and look for the
actions from the coffee app.
Here we can see the Open Favorites
intent we just created,
along with the title and description
we defined in the code.
Let's add it to the shortcut and run it.
The app should open and take us straight
to the favorites tab.
And that's it!
Our first App Intent is working!
This is the basic structure we use
for any task you create.
In the next videos, we explore other
types of results that
an intent can return,
like values, dialogues, and views.
Thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next video.