Hi! In this video, we are going to create
a shortcut using the app
intent we built in our last video.
We'll see how easy it is to turn
an intent into a shortcut
with very little extra code.
We also explore how to customize it.
Now, let's create a shortcut using
the app intent we built earlier.
We start by creating a new structure
called CoffeeShortcuts.
And we make it conform to the protocol
app shortcuts provider.
This tells the system that this structure
will provide shortcuts for our app.
Inside it, we must define a static list
called "appShortcuts",
where we can register
one or more shortcuts.
Here, we create a shortcut based on
the Open Favorites intent.
We also define a list of phrases that
the user can say to activate this shortcut.
In this case, open My Favorites,
followed by the app's name automatically.
These phrases are especially important
because they allow the user to interact
with the shortcut through Siri.
For now, we are keeping it simple
with just one phrase,
but in the next video,
we explore how to work with multiple phrases
and make this interaction even more powerful.
Finally, we give the shortcut
a "Short Title", which will be
displayed in the Shortcuts app.
And we set an icon for it using
the system image called "Heart.fill".
With just this, our shortcut is ready
and will appear
automatically in the Shortcuts app.
Now let's take a look at the result.
When you run the app and open
the Shortcuts app, we can already see our
new shortcut listed automatically.
It shows the title and the icon
we defined in the code, and it's fully ready
for the user to trigger
manually or by using Siri.
This integration happened
with just a few lines of code.
In addition to using the shortcuts inside
the Shortcuts app, the user can also
add it directly to the home screen.
This way, they can launch the shortcut
just like they would open a regular app,
making the experience even
faster and more convenient.
It's important to know that your app
can provide up to 10 shortcuts.
They will appear in the Shortcuts app
following the exact order you defined in
the array inside Coffee Shortcuts.
So, the first shortcut you add will be
the first shown
to the user, and so on.
And that's it!
Our first shortcut is working.
With just a few lines of code,
we connected our app to the shortcut system
and even made it possible for users
to add it to their home screen.
In the next video, we'll see how to use
Siri and Spotlight
to access this shortcut.
Thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next video.