Hi! In the last video, we created
an App intent that receives
a parameter and returns a value.
We also manually create a shortcut
that uses this value in a sequence of actions.
Now, let's check another
result an App Intent can provide
and how to create
a shortcut programmatically.
Let's Code!
In our ProductDetailIntent
perform function, let's add
Provides Dialog as a return,
so we return a dialog
to present it in a interactive way.
Here, we added
provides dialog as a return
of our intent perform function.
It gives us a dialog
as output in addition
to the return value that we also kept.
We added the IntentDialog
to the resulting structure
so the user can use these when
interacting with this intent.
We now have two possible ways of
interacting with our intent.
Let's create
a shortcut that uses our intent.
Let's rename it to My Coffee Shortcut.
Now, when using this shortcut,
it presents us the
dialog to input the product
and it presents the
output also in our dialog.
We can add the shortcut, set the
parameter in the intent
itself and it will use this
parameter to give us the price without
asking for the parameter.
In this video, we learn how to interact
with our intent using
shortcuts and dialogs.
In the next video, let's check how to
interact with it using Siri.
See you there!