Hi! In this video, we are starting our
hands-on journey with App Intents
by showing the sample app
we will use in this course.
It's a simple coffee shop app made
to help us focus
on creating and testing intents.
We'll show the main screens,
talk about the tools we are using,
and explain how the app is set up to make
learning App Intents easier.
Now, let's talk about
the tools we are using.
I'm running macOS version
15.4.1 and Xcode version 16.3.
If you are using macOS 15
or higher and Xcode 16 or above,
everything should work
just fine for this project.
I'm going to give you a quick demo
of the app we will use during this course.
It's a coffee shop app
with a few simple screens.
This is the menu, where
you can see a list of drinks
and snacks inspired by
coffee break traditions
from different countries.
It's a simple screen where
you can see each item's name,
price, and buttons to add
your favorites or to your bag.
This is where your favorite items appear.
If you go back to the menu,
tap the heart on one item
and return to the favorite screen,
you can see that the
item has been added here.
This screen shows the
orders you have made.
For now, we already have some
example orders listed here.
And when you add items
to your bag, they show up here.
If we go back to the menu, add an item
and return to the Bag screen,
you can change the quantity and
when you are ready, you can place an order.
This app was made simple on purpose,
so we can focus on learning how to use
App Intents without distractions.
For now, the list of items is fixed
and all of the data is saved only in memory.
There is no database
or permanent storage.
In the next videos, we'll start adding
App Intent files step by step.
And you only need to change
the app's code when it's really
necessary for a specific intent.
You can download the sample
project from the video page.
I recommend opening it in Xcode and
taking a few minutes
to explore the files and get
familiar with how the app is structured.
Don't worry, you don't need to understand
or memorize all of the code.
As we add App Intents in the next lessons,
we'll mostly be
writing new files, and in
most cases, we won't need
to change the existing code.
Thanks for watching, and we appreciate
you joining us on this journey.
In the next lessons, we'll work directly
with this app and code
to add useful and fun
integrations using App Intents.
You'll see how easy it is to make
your app more powerful
and connected across the system.
See you in the next video.
Bye!