Hi! In this video, we are going to talk
about a specific use case
for App Intents and Shortcuts,
using the squeeze gesture on
the Apple Pencil Pro. This is a good
example of how flexible these
tools are and how they can adapt to many
different ways users
interact with their devices.
The squeeze gesture is a small,
quick action that users can do by gently
pressing the Apple Pencil Pro.
It can be linked to different
features like opening a tool palette
or changing drawing modes
without interrupting the flow of what
the user is doing. It is just
one of the many ways the system
can respond to personal interaction styles.
As shown in the settings,
users can choose what
happens when they squeeze the pencil.
Some of the options
include showing the tool palette,
switching between tools or opening
the color picker. One of the
most powerful options is
selecting a shortcut. This allows users
to define exactly what they want the
gestures to trigger,
giving them full control over
the experience. With iPadOS, users can
connect this gesture to
a shortcut they have created in the
Shortcuts app. That means they can build
an automation that runs
instantly when they squeeze the pencil.
It is a very specific
scenario but as developers,
we can use the same App Intents and
Shortcuts we have already defined
to support it. This shows
how the work we do to support system
integrations can unlock
a wide range of user experiences.
From Shortcuts placed on the home screen
to very detailed gestures
like this one. Let's look at
a few examples. In a sketching app,
a squeeze might open the
brush picker. In a writing app,
it could switch between tools. But a user
could also create
a shortcut that opens ChatGPT
to ask a quick question or one that
starts a timer or pastes
a predefined text. Even small
automations like this can help users feel
more in control.
This gesture is just one case but it
highlights the power of App Intents
and Shortcuts. They are not
only for large actions or voice
commands. They can also support small
and precise interactions that
feel personal and natural.
Thanks for watching. Whether your app
supports drawing, writing
or something else entirely,
exploring different types of interactions
like this can help
you create a richer and
more responsive
experience for your app. Bye!