Hi! In this video, we are going to see
how to access this
shortcut we created using Siri.
We'll also explore how to add different
phrases to trigger the shortcut and check
how it appears in Spotlight Search.
The shortcut we created in the last video
is now fully integrated with Siri.
That means you can activate
it just by using your voice.
For example, you can say
"Open my favorites coffee" and
Siri will immediately run
the shortcut and open
the favorite screen in our app.
Now let's talk a bit more
about the Phrases property.
Each phrase you add here is interpreted
literally by Siri, so it's
important to think like your
users and try to anticipate the different
ways they might say the same command.
Also, every phrase must include the app's name.
That's why we use .applicationName
As a developer, it's a good practice
to provide several variations
of phrases for the same intent,
so users can naturally say what feels
right to them and still
get the expected result.
Here's an example where we added multiple
phrases to give the user more
flexibility when using Siri.
Now let's try out some of the phrases
we added and see how Siri responds.
I'm going to say a few
different variations, like
"show my favorites in Coffee"
and "go to favorites in Coffee".
And as you will see, Siri correctly
recognizes each one and
runs the shortcut we created.
And the best part is that we don't need
to write any extra code for our shortcut
to appear in Spotlight.
The setup we already created is enough.
You can access it by pulling down to open
Spotlight and typing the name of the app
or even part of the shortcut's title.
And that's it for this
module, thanks for watching!
We have seen how to create an app intent,
turn it into a shortcut, and make it
accessible through Siri and Spotlight.
In the upcoming modules, we'll go further
and learn how to build
more complex intents,
integrated with additional system
features, to make your
app even more powerful.
Thanks for watching and I'll
see you in the next module.
Bye.