Hello! In the previous module, we learned
how to add a parameter to an app intent
to make it customizable.
We also saw how to use this parameter
with shortcuts, Siri, and widgets.
So far, we have used just primitive types
as parameters, which limits control
and makes natural language interactions,
like full sentence Siri requests,
less effective.
Hi, my name is Sergio and we will see how
to overcome these
limitations using App entities.
An App entity is a concept that your app
exposed to the App Intent system.
It's a powerful abstraction that allows
custom, dynamic data to be used in
shortcuts and widgets.
Let's take a new item as an example of
an entity our app can expose.
Here's our MenuItemEntity.switt
To be used as an entity, the type must
conform to the AppEntity protocol.
Let's highlight the key elements.
The ID is a unique
identifier for the entity.
The property of our name makes name
available for App Intent to be used
directly in phrases.
The display representation controls how
the entity appears to the users.
Here we use only the name.
The typeDisplayRepresentation is
a user facing string that
describes the kind of entity.
We define it as product.
And finally, the initializer let us
easily convert from a MenuItem model
to our MenuItemEntity structure.
But we're still missing the lookup
mechanism, the defaultQuery.
Let's implement the menu item query,
which is responsible for
searching and suggesting items.
This structure conforms to the entity
string query protocol.
Let's break it down.
Entities for
Retrieves entities by their IDs,
required by all queries.
Entities matching allows
searching by a text string.
In our case, we search the
product name in our model.
Suggested entities returns a default list,
such as favorites are top sellers,
that shows up as autocomplete suggestions.
And now, let's use this
entity in an actual intent.
The key change here is using the
MenuItemEntity instead of a raw string
in the parameter attribute.
Then, in the perform function,
we use this entity to fetch the actual model
data from our system.
Now, to make the suggestions work
dynamically, we must notify the system
whenever they change.
Let's do this in the app setup using
the update app shortcuts parameters function.
And that's it!
Now, we have a fully working Intent that
uses a real entity from our app model,
enabling better Siri integration,
widget suggestions, and more
natural shortcut interactions.
In the next video, we'll explore how
to create and use these shortcuts,
both manually and programmatically.
See you there!